Maxx King

San Diego, CA | (201) 414-8847 | maxxking98@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/maxx-king

Website Portfolio: https://maxxking.dev

Software Engineer with over 2 years of experience in full-stack development and a passion for learning new technologies. As Scrum Master, lead a team of 10 developers through various feature launches. Proactively takes an iterative development approach that focuses on experimentation to drive effective decisions.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer, Jr.

ClearHello, Escondido, CA

February 2022 – Present

- As Scrum Master, lead a team of 10 developers deploying both front end and back end solutions across multiple brands. Oversaw the launch of two major, customer-facing features and continued iterating on the product.
- Increased automated testing coverage by 28%. Introduced a tool to give developers the ability to easily identify lines in code that remained untested in order to enhance development speed and reduce errors in a CI/CD pipeline.
- Successfully migrated legacy PERL code to modern solutions such as Node, TypeScript, Angular, and React.
- Utilized Google Lighthouse to increase accessibility by 16%, SEO (Search Engine Optimization) by 12%, and page loading performance by 8%.
- Created documentation for legacy components to ensure future developers could more quickly and easily have a thorough understanding of business critical workflows, mitigating the chance of errors re-emerging in the future.

Coding Instructor

Wiz Kid Coding

June 2021 – August 2021

Led a dynamic classroom of 5-10 students, cultivating a vibrant and engaging learning atmosphere across diverse skill levels. Developed tailored lesson plans, instructing the fundamentals of scripting (Lua), and imparted essential principles of effective coding practices.

Software Engineer Intern

Isobar US, New York, NY

June 2015 - July 2015

Enhanced proficiency in HTML/CSS and mastered the JavaScript tech stack through hands-on projects and real-world applications for various clients.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

December 2021

Skills

 $\textbf{Technologies:} \ HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Perl, Java, Python, C++, Php, MySQL, React, Node, Python, Python$

Angular, Git, Docker, AWS, REST API

Soft-Skills: Data analytics, Database management, Project management, Communication with non-technical team members, Problem Solving, Pattern recognition